Inventory of the Joel Martin Halpern papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Laos file
  - Letters from Tom Dooley, 1958-1962 (Folder 27: 14)
- Printed matter
  - Yugoslavia handbook, 1977 (Folder 27: 15)
  - Academic papers, 1989, undated (Folder 27: 16)
- Laos file
  - Field notes, research, and grants, 1958-1970 (Folder 28: 1-6)
    Photocopies. Includes field notes from 1959 and 1969, document in Lao script, and application for SEADAG research grant
  - Field notes, correspondence, and related documents, 1956-1959 (Folder 29: 1-3)
- Writings and printed matter, 1970-1991 (Folder 29: 4-6)
- Printed matter, 1952-1991 (Folder 30: 1-3)
- Writings
  - Preliminary copies, printed copies, and notes, 1965-1973 (Folder 30: 4)
- Photographs
  - Slides of Tom Dooley and flyer for "The Peoples and Cultures of Indochina,", undated (Folder 30: 5)
- Conference materials and research outlines, 1970, undated (Folder 30: 6)
- Laos file
  - Notes and printed matter on Hmong people, undated (Folder 30: 7)
- Yugoslavia file
  - Orašac
    - Emigrants from Orašac, 1966 (Folder 30: 8-16)
    - Marriage statistics from 1870 to 1965, 1966 (Folder 30: 17-19)
    - Census, 1953 (Folder 31: 1)
    - Engagement book for 1907 to 1954, 1975 (Folder 31: 2-4)
    - Birth statistics, 1975 (Folder 31: 5)
- Subject file
  - Filipec, Jindrich, 1974 (Folder 31: 6)
  - Friedberg, Maurice, 1972 (Folder 31: 7)
  - Gantskaya, O. A., 1973 (Folder 31: 8)
  - Richta, Radovan, 1974 (Folder 31: 9)
  - Rudnytsky, Ivan, 1970 (Folder 31: 10)
  - Singleton, Fred, 1970-1971, undated (Folder 31: 11)
  - Smemo, Kenneth, undated (Folder 31: 12)
- Printed matter on Russia, Bulgaria, and Yugoslavia, 1966-1991 (Folder 31: 13-15)
- Society for Slovene Studies, meeting minutes and financial report, 1987 (Folder 31: 16)
- Yugoslavia Project outline by Halpern, circa 1961 (Folder 31: 17)
- Biographical file
  - Documents related to accusations of Halpern's involvement with United States intelligence services, 1960-1978 (Folder 31: 18)
- Photographs
  - Khristo Botev slides, circa 1983 (Folder 32: 1)
- Senate hearing before Subcommittee on African Affairs, 1968 (Folder 32: 2)
- UCLA file
  - No Lit publishing house invoices for library, 1962 (Folder 32: 2-4)
    Includes invoices for UCLA library
- Subject file
  - Kranjec, Silvo, 1966 (Folder 32: 5)
  - Salzmann, Zdenek, undated (Folder 32: 6)
  - Sanders, Irwin, 1973 (Folder 32: 7)
- Yugoslavia file
  - Notes on "Ljubljana, Images from its History,", undated (Folder 32: 8)
  - Šenčur, Solvenia land holding statistics from the 1800s, undated (Folder 32: 9)
- UCLA file
  - American Council of Learned Societies project and library acquisitions, 1961-1973 (Folder 33: 1-7)
    Project to create a "Handbook of Library and Research Resources on East Central and Southeastern Europe"
- Printed matter and conference materials, 1982-1991 (Folder 33: 8-9)
- Printed matter and conference materials, 1960-1991 (Folder 34: 1-3)
- Writings
  - "A Brief Survey of English Language Research on Yugoslav Cultural and Social Anthropology and Ethnology," typescript, 1970 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Typescripts and printed copies, 1957-1975 (Folder 34: 5-7)
    Includes writings on Laos and Yugoslavia
- Printed matter
  - Pašic, 1927 (Folder 35: 1)
    In Serbian
  - "Yugoslav Research Guide,", 1969 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Belgrade book fair catalog, 1967 (Folder 35: 3)
- Cambodian Crisis Committee II, 1983-1986 (Folder 35: 4-7)
  Organization in Amherst, Massachusetts, to aid Cambodian refugees
- Writings
  - General, 1973-1988 (Folder 36: 1)
    Includes Pregled, issue 237
  - Bibliographies created by Halpern, 1961-1975 (Folder 36: 2-3)
  - University of Massachusetts at Amherst International Area Studies Programs Occasional Paper Series, printed copies, 1978-1989 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Printed copies on Yugoslavia, Laos, Bulgaria, and Canada, 1965-1991 (Folder 36: 5)
  - Typescripts and printed copies, including conference papers, 1973-1992 (Folder 36: 6)
- Yugoslavia file
  - Yugoslavia projects and courses, 1973-1986 (Folder 36: 7)
    Includes correspondence, research, and course material
  - Yugoslavia projects and courses, 1951-1992 (Box 37)
    Includes description of "The Far World Comes Near" photograph exhibit, correspondence concerning an ICAES conference in Zagreb, and course description of "Rural and Peasant Societies"
- Russian Research Center, Harvard University, 1951 (Box 37)
- Printed matter
  - Academic papers on Armenia, 1979-1984 (Box 37)
    Materials from a conference in 1979
  - Nolit catalogs (Box 37)
- Yugoslavia file, Orašac research
  - Census from 1800s (Box 37)
- Writings
  - "Life in a Shuridian Village," by Joel and Barbara Halpern, 1956 (Box 37)
- Subject file
  - USSR politics, 1973-1987 (Folder 38: 1)
- Printed matter, 1972-2006 (Folder 38: 2-5)
- Photographs
  - Hmong in Laos, 2007 (Folder 38: 6)
- Printed matter and miscellaneous, 1988-2007 (Box 39)
  Includes Sofia News, Society for Solvene Studies meeting minutes, and documents from a trip in 1990
- Conference file
  - Soviet and East European agriculture conference, UC Santa Barbara, 1964-1965 (Box 40: 1)
- Course material
  - Rural and Peasant Societies course, 1980-1990 (Box 40: 2)
- Society for Slovene Studies, 2003 (Box 40: 3)
- Printed matter, 1975-2006 (Box 40: 4-6)
- Writings
  - Printed copies, 1973, 1986-1989 (Folder 41: 1)
  - "Traditionelle Wermuster un der Krieg in Ex-Jugoslawien," printed copy, 1994 (Folder 41: 2)
  - Mekong Basin Development, Laos and Thailand, Selected Bibliographies, 1974 (Folder 41: 3)
  - People in States textbook, 1972 (Folder 41: 4)
- Genealogical record for Eskimo families of Anaktuvuk Pass, undated (Folder 41: 5)
- International Research and Exchanges Board, 1973-1978 (Folder 41: 6)
- Moerman, Michael, 1960 (Folder 41: 7)
- Conference file
  - Conference on Peasantry in Eastern Europe, 1975-1976 (Folder 41: 8)
- Biographical file
  - Curriculum vitae, 1990 (Folder 42: 1)
- Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Folder 42: 2)
- Printed matter, 1931-1992 (Folder 42: 3-6)
- USSR (Box 43: 1-2)
  Includes typescript chapters of unidentified book, possibly by Halpern
- Printed matter, 1962-1986 (Box 43: 3-4)
- Conference file
  - Social Science History Association conference program, 1992 (Box 43: 5)
- Biographical file
  - Curriculum vitae of Halpern, 1990 (Box 43: 6)
- Writings
  - Typescripts and correspondence, 1969-1986 (Box 43: 7)
    Includes writing by Joseph Obrebski edited by Barbara Halpern
- Water and jungle survival field tests of Air Force reports and comparative education conference proceedings, 1956-1958 (Folder 44: 1)
- Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (SEADAG) papers and seminar reports, 1971-1974 (Folder 44: 2-3)
- American-Yugoslav Project in Regional and Urban Planning Studies, 1966-1972 (Folder 44: 4-5)
- American-Yugoslav Project in Regional and Urban Planning Studies (Contd.), 1966-1972 (Folder 45: 1-5)
- Voelkner, Henry, 1968-1969 (Folder 45: 6)
- Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (SEADAG)
  - Executive committee meeting minutes, correspondence, grant proposals and evaluations, 1968-1969 (Folder 46: 1-9)
  - Grant proposals and evaluations, 1968-1969 (Folder 47: 1-4)
  - Research proposal of Halpern and Henry Homes, 1961, 1968 (Folder 47: 5)
- Course material
  - Graduate seminar in anthropology at Brandeis University, 1964 (Folder 47: 6)
- Research proposal of Halpern submitted to the Ford Foundation and the Rockefeller Foundation Program in Population Policy Research, circa 1973-1974 (Folder 47: 7)
- Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (SEADAG)
  - Grant proposals and evaluations, 1968-1969 (Folder 48: 1-5)
- Writings
  - "Yesterday's People: Peasants of Polesie" exhibition by Joseph Obrebski, 1973 (Folder 48: 6)
    Forward by Halpern
  - Anthropology of East Europe Review, correspondence, printed copy, and papers of others, 1992 (Folder 49: 1)
    Edited by Halpern
  - General, 1970-1992 (Folder 49: 2)
- Milovan Danojlić typescripts, 1974, 1981, undated (Folder 49: 3-6)
  Includes Stranstvovanje and poetry. In Serbian.
- American-Yugoslav Project in Regional and Urban Planning Studies, reports and conference excerpts, 1966-1972 (Box 50)
- American-Yugoslav Project in Regional and Urban Planning Studies, reports, 1970, 1977 (Folder 51: 1)
- Printed matter, 1965-1990 (Folder 51: 2-4)
  Includes Yugoslavia travel brochures
- Russian Research Center, Harvard University, conference schedule, 1977 (Folder 51: 5)
- Writings by Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern and coding instructions for Yugoslav interviews, 1961-1987 (Folder 51: 6)
- Subject file
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1969 (Folder 52: 1)
  - Association for the Study of Man-Environment Relations, 1969 (Folder 52: 2)
  - Ekistics, 1965-1969 (Folder 52: 3)
    Includes printed matter on Doxiadis Associates
  - Serbian, Slovene, and Eastern Europe studies, 1980-1987 (Folder 52: 4)
- Printed matter, 1964-1983 (Folder 52: 5-6)
- Writings
  - "Tribal People of Laos," typescript, and "Demographic and Social Change in the Village of Orašac,", 1966, 1976 (Folder 53: 1)
- Printed matter and conference material, 1956-1980 (Folder 53: 2-6)
  Includes material on Yiddish studies and ethnographic data
- U.S. riot data, Lemberg Center for the Study of Violence, Brandeis University, 1968 (Folder 54: 1)
- Printed matter, 1965-1979 (Folder 54: 2-5)
- Biographical file
  - Curriculum vitae of Halpern, 1988 (Folder 55: 1)
- American-Yugoslav Project in Regional and Urban Planning Studies, reports, 1969-1970 (Folder 55: 2-4)
- Writings
  - Printed copies and typescripts, 1968-1994 (Folder 55: 5)
- Printed matter, 1961-1990 (Folder 56: 1)
- Subject file
  Mainly speeches and writings by others
  - American culture, 1965-1975 (Folder 56: 2)
  - Field, Mark G., USSR health, 1961-1970 (Folder 56: 3-5)
  - Frisch, Rose, food supplies and population growth, 1970 (Folder 56: 6)
  - Frey, Frederick W., 1964-1966 (Folder 57: 1)
  - Hopper, Rex and research on Latin America, 1963-1995 (Folder 57: 2)
  - Hughes, Everett, 1963 (Folder 57: 3)
  - Laird, Roy and Betty, agricultural revolution, 1967 (Folder 57: 4)
  - McClelland, David C., 1957 (Folder 57: 5)
  - Moore, Wilbert E., circa 1966 (Folder 57: 6)
- Testimony of Halpern in deportation case, 1995 (Folder 58: 1)
- Society for Slovene Studies, 1974-1986 (Folder 58: 2)
- Subject file
  - Agricultural economics in China and Taiwan, 1961, 1966 (Folder 58: 3)
  - China agrarian policy, source materials, 1952, 1966 (Folder 58: 4)
  - China, 1961, undated (Folder 58: 5)
  - Cattell, David T., crica 1957 (Folder 58: 6)
  - Hocevar, Toussaint, 1979 (Folder 58: 7)
  - Jowitt, Kenneth, 1964 (Folder 58: 8)
  - Kolaja, Jiri, 1968, undated (Folder 58: 9)
  - Nimitz, Nancy, 1965 (Folder 58: 10)
  - Rothman, Stanley, undated (Folder 58: 11)
  - Stuart, Robert C., undated (Folder 58: 12)
  - Wharton, Clifton R., Jr., 1962-1963 (Folder 58: 13-14)
  - Tominaga, Ken'ichi, undated (Folder 58: 15)
  - Velikonja, Joseph, 1968 (Folder 58: 16)
- Conference file
  - Hmong in America conference flyer, 1995 (Folder 59: 1)
- Subject file
  - Adler, Franz, 1947-1980 (Folder 59: 2)
  - Black, Cyril E., Russian history and modernization, 1960, undated (Folder 59: 3)
  - Lodge, George C., 1966, undated (Folder 59: 4)
  - McNeill, W. H., modern world, undated (Folder 59: 5)
  - Moore, Wilbert E., 1946-1966 (Folder 59: 6)
  - Nelson, Joan, undated (Folder 59: 7)
  - Pye, Lucian W., 1959 (Folder 59: 8)
  - Ryavec, Karl W., 1970 (Folder 59: 9)
  - Volin, Lazar, 1953-1960 (Folder 59: 10)
  - Weil, Irwin, 1965 (Folder 59: 11)
  - Korbonski, Andzej, 1963-1975 (Folder 60: 1)
  - National Council for Soviet and East European Research, 1984-1985 (Folder 60: 2)
  - Czech bibliography on the Balkans, 1970 (Folder 60: 3)
  - Yugoslavia and Southeast Asia, circa 1963-1968 (Folder 60: 4)
  - Agricultural economy, 1959-1967 (Folder 60: 5)
  - Hoffman, George, 1966, undated (Folder 60: 6)
  - Regional planning, J. Fisher, undated (Folder 60: 7)
  - Volgyes, Ivan, undated (Folder 60: 8)
  - Griffith, Willam E., Eastern European studies, 1964-1965 (Folder 60: 9)
  - Hungary agriculture, peasant society, 1959-1989 (Folder 60: 10)
- Printed matter, 1970-1995 (Folder 61: 1)
  Includes Council on International Educational Exchange booklets
- Subject file
  - Agricultural economics, 1958-1962 (Folder 61: 2-3)
  - Agricultural extension, 1952-1974 (Folder 61: 4)
  - France, agriculture, 1971 (Folder 61: 5)
  - Indonesia, 1965-1966 (Folder 61: 6)
  - Indonesian/Chinese, 1962-1967 (Folder 61: 7)
  - Southeast European studies, 1975-1981 (Folder 61: 8)
  - Ecology, United States, 1967-1969, undated (Folder 61: 9)
  - Brode, John, 1962 (Folder 62: 1)
  - Brower, Daniel R., undated (Folder 62: 2)
  - Brozek, Josef, 1959-1965 (Folder 62: 3)
  - Bush, Keith, 1974 (Folder 62: 4)
  - Cieplak, Tadeusz, Poland, 1972 (Folder 62: 5)
- American-Yugoslav Exchange Program seminars, 1968 (Folder 62: 6)
- Printed matter and conference material, 1957-1994 (Folder 62: 7-10)
- Printed matter and conference material, 1963-1992 (Folder 63: 1-6)
  Includes conference papers of the International Association of Southeast European Studies and a paper prepared for the American-Yugoslav Seminar
- Trip of 1961, travel brochures, 1958-1961 (Folder 64: 1-6)
  Booklets from 1961 trip to USSR, Poland, Romania, Bulgaria, and Greece
- Writings
  - "A Yugoslav View of American Anthropological Fieldwork in Serbia: A Journalistic TV Documentary on the Work of Joel M. Halpern and Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern," script, 1986 (Folder 65: 1)
- Printed matter
  - General, 1961-1976 (Folder 65: 2-7)
  - International Association of Southeast European Studies, 1966 (Folder 66: 1)
  - Printed matter on China and Afghanistan, 1959-1984 (Folder 66: 2)
- Lecture schedule for MIT-Wellesley seminar on development and reading list for CIEE-Fudan summer program, 1979, 1981 (Folder 66: 3)
- Subject file
  - China, 1961-1995 (Folder 66: 4-7)
- Conference file
  - Soviet-Asian Relations Conference, University of Southern California, conference reports, 1959 (Folder 67: 1)
- Writings
  - Typescripts and printed copies, 1969-1973 (Folder 67: 2)
- Trip of 1961, travel brochures and other printed matter, 1958-1961 (Folder 67: 3-5)
- Yugoslavia file
  - Orašac field data, kinship charts, circa 1966-1970s (Folder 67: 6)
  - Archival research, undated (Folder 67: 7)
  - Oršac field notes, 1953-1954 (Folder 67: 8)
  - Orašac kinship charts, undated (Folder 68: 1)
    Household data from 1961 and 1975 census
- Papers by Damir Mirkovic, Brandeis University, 1964-1968 (Folder 68: 2)
- Writings
  - Typescripts and printed copies, 1950-1992 (Folder 68: 3-4)
- Subject file
  - Poland, 1964-1967 (Folder 68: 5)
- Printed matter
  - International Association of Southeast European Studies conference publications and bulletins, 1970-1972 (Folder 68: 6-8)
  - International Association of Southeast European Studies bulletins, 1971-1974 (Folder 69: 1-3)
  - Croatia statistics, 1955-1957 (Folder 69: 4-6)
- Letter to Albert C. Spaulding, 1961 (Folder 69: 7)
- Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern file
  - Letters to Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern from Bulgarians, 1990-1995 (Box 70-78)
    Letters in English and Bulgarian regarding multiple sclerosis
- Printed matter
  - Yugoslavia articles, print outs from Internet news digests, 1991-1996 (Box 79-88)
    Electronic bulletins related to states in former Yugoslavia and the Yugoslav civil war
  - General, 1956-1975 (Folder 89: 1-5)
- Conference file
  - Sociological Association of Serbia, social changes in rural areas conference papers, 1977 (Folder 89: 6)
  - Conference materials and papers, 1979-1996 (Folder 90: 1)
- Library of Congress Yugoslavia Project, circa 1962 (Folder 90: 2)
  See also files on UCLA library collecting
- Printed matter, 1950-1979 (Folder 90: 3-8)
- Conference file
  - Yale University seminar, 1996 (Folder 91: 1)
  - Five College Program in Peace and World Security Studies, 1995 (Folder 91: 2)
- Russian Research Center, Harvard University, calendar, 1996 (Folder 91: 3)
- Writings
  - "Time: A Tripartite Sociotemporal Model," printed copy, 1996 (Folder 91: 4)
- Kragujevac project, 1964 (Folder 91: 5)
- Printed matter, 1961-1997 (Folder 91: 6-11)
  Includes Cornell newsletters and a urban plan of Zagreb
- Laos file
  - Account of trip with viceroy/prince of Laos and letter, 1957-1958 (Folder 91: 12)
- CLOSED (Box 92-95)
- Subject file
  - United States culture, 1972-1974 (Folder 96: 1-3)
- University of Massachusetts, Amherst
  - Dissertation prospectus of Dennis Vnenchak, 1975 (Folder 96: 4)
    Halpern was on guidance committee
  - Handbook, report, and newsletters, 1997 (Folder 96: 5)
- Photographs
  - Photocopies of photographs of Župča, Bosnia, 1961-1962 (Folder 96: 6)
    Photographs part of a research project of Halpern in collaboration with the Zemaljski Museum in Sarajevo. Includes notations from 1997.
- Subject file
  - United States, 1960-1974 (Folder 97: 1-11)
    Includes files on rural and urban life, social structure, poverty, and American culture
- Paper by Robert Wandruff, Brandeis University, 1965 (Folder 98: 1)
- Writings, conference materials, and academic papers by others, 1986, 1995 (Folder 98: 2)
- Cambodia New Year Celebration flyer, 1986 (Folder 98: 3)
  Halpern served on the organizing committee
- Printed matter
  - Croatia statistics, 1956, 1961 (Folder 98: 4-5)
  - Pregled magazines, 1960-1973 (Folder 98: 6-8)
  - Croatia statistics, 1961 (Folder 99: 1)
  - General, 1961-1971 (Folder 99: 2-3)
- Course materials
  - Eastern Europe courses, 1965-1986 (Folder 99: 4-10)
    Includes course materials from courses Halpern taught at various universities, including courses on rural-peasant society and the USSR
- Writings and conference material, 1970, 1995 (Folder 99: 11)
- Subject file
  - Association for Asian Studies and Western Distributors of Books, 1972, undated (Folder 100: 1)
  - Bulgaria, 1976, 1994 (Folder 100: 2)
    Includes materials for Bulgaria Radio Free Europe and meeting of Bulgarian and North American scholars
  - Development, 1961-1964 (Folder 100: 3)
  - Education, international and intercultural exchange, 1962-1965 (Folder 100: 4)
  - Krutilla, John V., 1963-1967 (Folder 100: 5)
  - Slavonic studies, Cambridge bibliography, undated (Folder 100: 6)
  - Warner, Edward L., 1992 (Folder 100: 7)
  - Wyzan, Michael L., 1982, undated (Folder 100: 8)
- North American Society for Servian Studies, membership for Halpern, 1992 (Folder 100: 9)
- Printed matter
  - General, 1962-2005 (Folder 100: 10-13)
  - Amherst, 1985, 1987 (Folder 100: 14)
  - Center for Slavic and East European Studies, UC Berkeley, 1969-1971 (Folder 100: 15)
- Subject file
  - Foreign Leader Program, 1963 (Folder 101: 1)
  - Kadic, Ante, undated (Folder 101: 2-3)
  - Japan, 1955-1973 (Folder 101: 4-5)
  - Kossev, Dimiter, Bulgaria, undated (Folder 101: 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1992-2004 (Folder 101: 7)
    Includes conference material and letter from Anthony Lake
  - Weil, Irwin, 1962-1965 (Folder 101: 8)
  - Weiner, Myron, 1963-1965 (Folder 101: 9)
  - Williamson, Robert C., political violence, rural Columbia, 1965 (Folder 101: 10)
- Printed matter, 1970-1998 (Folder 101: 11-14)
- Conference file, 1964, 1995-1999 (Folder 101: 15)
- Writings
  - Book reviews by Halpern, correspondence and typescript, 1998 (Folder 101: 16)
- Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern file
  - Program pamphlets and curriculum vitae, undated (Folder 101: 17)
- Printed matter
  - General, 1977-1989 (Folder 102: 1)
  - Sofia News, 1988 (Folder 102: 2)
- Subject file
  - Anthropology, 1998 (Folder 102: 3)
  - China, 1974-1997 (Folder 102: 4)
  - Yugoslavia, 1988-1998 (Folder 102: 5)
- Subject file
  - Eastern Europe and USSR, 1955-1970 (Folder 103: 1)
    Includes materials from Halpern's time at the Russian Research Center at Harvard University
- Printed matter
  - Preporod Ili Smrt, monograph and form letter, 1985 (Folder 103: 2)
  - Serbian Struggle magazines, 1985 (Folder 103: 3)
    Includes article on Slobodan Draskovich
  - General, 1961-1994 (Folder 103: 4-8)
  - General, 1940-1994 (Folder 104: 1-3)
  - The Journal of the British Yugoslav Society, 1968-1974 (Folder 104: 4)
- Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern file
  - "Barbara Halpern Invites You to Focus on People" pamphlet, undated (Folder 104: 5)
- Subject file
  - Milenkovitch, Deborah D., 1976 (Folder 104: 6)
  - Campbell, Robert W., 1965 (Folder 104: 7)
  - Djordjevic, J., 1963 (Folder 104: 8)
  - Communist Party government line-up, Yugoslavia, 1976 (Folder 104: 9)
- American Association for Slavic Studies, 1973-1974 (Folder 104: 10)
- Yugoslav Press and Cultural Center program, 1977 (Folder 104: 11)
- Correspondence, 1976, 1996 (Folder 104: 12)
  Includes letters of M. A. Branch, Paul Shoup, Joseph Stipanovich, and Ivan Volgyes
- Writings
  - Typescripts and printed copies, 1985-1989, undated (Folder 104: 13)
- Conference file
  - Second International Congress of Southeast European Studies, International Association of Southeast European Studies, Athens, 1968-1970 (Folder 105: 1)
    Includes correspondence and conference program
- Printed matter
  - Institute of Architecture and Town Planning of Serbia, 1981-1989 (Folder 105: 2)
  - General, 1966-1990 (Folder 105: 3-7)
- Subject file
  - Biographical data on Croatians in the United States, 1964-1965 (Folder 106: 1)
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1960 (Folder 106: 2)
  - Gobetz, Giles, 1971-1976 (Folder 106: 3)
  - Hammond, Thomas T., 1955 (Folder 106: 4)
  - Hocevar, Toussaint, 1971, undated (Folder 106: 5)
  - Klein, George, 1971-1977 (Folder 106: 6)
  - Milenkovitch, Michael M., 1968-1977 (Folder 106: 7)
- Printed matter
  - That's Yugoslavia: Information and Facts, 1982 (Folder 106: 8)
  - Bulgarian Studies Association newsletters, 1984-2002 (Folder 106: 9)
- Subject file
  - Denitch, Bogdan and Despalatovic, Elinor Murray, 1971-1989 (Folder 107: 1)
  - Dirlam, Joel E., circa 1967 (Folder 107: 2)
  - Drachkovitch, Milorad M., 1964 (Folder 107: 3)
  - Gruenwald, Oskar, 1977 (Folder 107: 4)
  - Hammond, Thomas, 1963-1965 (Folder 107: 5-6)
  - Kelley, Donald R., 1972 (Folder 107: 7)
  - Klein, George and McCrea, Barbara, 1976-1978, undated (Folder 107: 8)
  - Klein, George and Patricia, 1976 (Folder 107: 9)
  - Pipes, Richard, 1959-1968 (Folder 107: 10)
  - Terry, Sarah Meiklejohn, 1984 (Folder 107: 11)
- Coding instructions for Yugoslav interviews, 1961-1962 (Folder 107: 12)
- Subject file
  - Association for the Study of the Nationalities (USSR and East Europe), 1971-1972 (Folder 108: 1)
  - Drachkovitch, Milorad D., 1969, undated (Folder 108: 2)
    Includes note by Halpern from 2005
  - Jugoslav Institute of Economic Research, 1958-1963 (Folder 108: 3)
  - Politika, Yugoslavia urbanization and agricultural news, 1964-1965 (Folder 108: 4)
  - Society for Slovene Studies, 1993-1996 (Folder 108: 5)
  - Ulam, Adam, 1967-1968 (Folder 108: 6)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, Yugoslavia agriculture reports, 1960-1978 (Folder 108: 7)
  - Vlachos, Evan, 1972, 1976 (Folder 108: 8)
  - Vucinich, Nicholas, undated (Folder 108: 9)
  - Yugoslavia bibliography of the GLCA Yugoslav-American seminar, 1969 (Folder 108: 10)
- Printed matter, 1963-1997 (Folder 108: 11-13)
- Conference flyers and Bulgaria-Irrigation Restructuring and Rehabilitation Project, 1966-1997 (Folder 108: 14)
- Textbooks and published education aids, 1918-1936, 1953-1987 (Box 109-111)
- Printed matter (monographs), 1931-1986 (Box 112-113)
  Mainly bibliographic catalogs in Croatian and Yugoslavia scientific guides
- Audiovisual material (Box 114)
  - Russian tape, Moscow "Good Even" TV show, news, undated (Box 114)
    One VHS tape
  - Halpernovi u Orašcu, Serbian TV, 1986 (Box 114)
  - "Die Verbrechen Des Kroatischen Staates An Serben Und Angehoerigen Der Armee," Croatian crimes against Serbs, official Serbian version, 1991-1993 (Box 114)